<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on 5ysk3y Pwnz</title>
    <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on 5ysk3y Pwnz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://5ysk3y.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anonymous - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/thm/guides/anonymous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/thm/guides/anonymous/</guid>
      <description>Overview Welcome to this walkthrough of the TryHackMe room, Anonymous .
This Medium Linux room leverages anonymous access to an FTP service in order to modify a script that&amp;rsquo;s run via cron every five minutes. This gets us a user shell and, from there, we abuse a SUID binary to get ourselves a root shell. All in all, this is a fun room to accomplish and has touches of OSCP-like concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Zone - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/thm/guides/gamezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/thm/guides/gamezone/</guid>
      <description>Overview Today I&amp;rsquo;ll be bringing you a guide for the Try Hack Me room, Gamezone . This is an invaluable room for anyone looking to familiarize themselves with OSCP level concepts as the first stage leverages an ORDER BY/UNION SQL injection. During this walkthrough we&amp;rsquo;re going to manually exploit the injection, instead of relying on SQLMap to do it for us, in order to get a password. From there we use SSH Port Forwarding to gain access to a Webmin service that&amp;rsquo;s locked down, before we use metasploit to compromise that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAdmin [Easy] - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/openadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/openadmin/</guid>
      <description>Overview OpenAdmin was a quick and easy Linux box that uses a common CVE for an application called ONA to get us intial access to the box. From there, we hop between 2 user through some enumeration before exploiting a sudo command to get root.
 NMAP Scan Let&amp;rsquo;s begin by seeing what ports are currently open:
# Nmap 7.80 scan initiated Sat Jan 4 19:56:44 2020 as: nmap -v -A -oA nmap/openadmin_initial 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registry [Hard] - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/registry/</guid>
      <description>Overview Registry is an amazing Linux machine - it&amp;rsquo;s rated as hard but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all too difficult. That said it was very enjoyable and involves you, firstly, taking advantage of a Docker API to pull down an image from a Registry on the box. From there we get a shell and proceed to gain access to a hosted CMS called Bolt; this enables us to execute code as the www-data user which, conveniently, also has sudo access to a binary that can perform full system backups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
