<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hack The Box on 5ysk3y Pwnz</title>
    <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/tags/hack-the-box/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hack The Box on 5ysk3y Pwnz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://5ysk3y.github.io/tags/hack-the-box/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAdmin [Easy] - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/openadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/openadmin/</guid>
      <description>OpenAdmin was a quick and easy Linux box that uses a common CVE for an application called ONA to get us intial access to the box. From there, we hop between 2 user through some enumeration before exploiting a sudo command to get root.
nMap Scan Let&amp;rsquo;s begin by seeing what ports are currently open:
# Nmap 7.80 scan initiated Sat Jan 4 19:56:44 2020 as: nmap -v -A -oA nmap/openadmin_initial 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registry [Hard] - Linux</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/registry/</guid>
      <description>Registry is an amazing Linux machine - it&amp;rsquo;s rated as hard but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it all too difficult. That said it was very enjoyable and involves you, firstly, taking advantage of a Docker API to pull down an image from a Registry on the box. From there we get a shell and proceed to gain access to a hosted CMS called Bolt; this enables us to execute code as the www-data user which, conveniently, also has sudo access to a binary that can perform full system backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sniper [Medium] - Windows</title>
      <link>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/sniper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://5ysk3y.github.io/htb/guides/sniper/</guid>
      <description>Sniper was one of my favorite boxes from recent memory. It leverages an RFI and Powershell constrained mode to eventually get a user shell. From there you poison a Windows Help (CHM) file in order to execute code as the Administrator user. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how I did it. Please also note that the first part of this leverages a python script that I created; it&amp;rsquo;s referenced and included as a gist for your viewing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>